{"tossups": [{"question": "This ruler signed the Peace of Vervins to end a war with Spain. The Duc de Sully and this ruler defeated the Count of Egmont at the Battle of Ivry. This ruler, who was assassinated by the zealot Francois Ravaillac, was married to (*) Marie de Medici, who later led the \u201cDay of the Dupes\u201d against Cardinal Richelieu. This ruler gave protective rights to the Huguenots through the Edict of Nantes. For 10 points, name this French king, the first ruler from the Bourbon dynasty who once said \u201cParis is well worth a mass.\u201d", "answer": "Henry IV [accept Henry of Navarre; prompt on \u201cHenry\u201d]", "subcategory": "History European", "category": "History"}, {"question": "The value of virial coefficients depend on this quantity. The wavelength corresponding to the maximum intensity of radiation emitted by a black body is inversely proportional to this quantity, according to Wien\u2019s law, and the total intensity of radiation is proportional to the (*) fourth power of this quantity. According to the Joule-Thomson effect, this quantity decreases for a gas upon expansion, as it is directly proportional to volume, as well as pressure. For 10 points, name this quantity which is measured in Celsius or Kelvins.", "answer": "Temperature", "subcategory": "Science Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "After Ravana sang the Shiva Tandava Stotram, Shiva was so impressed that he gifted him one of these objects. In the Cantar de Mio Cid, one of these objects named Tizona scared Ferran Gonzalez so much that he refused to fight. One of these objects named Kusanagi was obtained from Yamato-no-orochi\u2019s belly after it was slain by Susano\u2019o. Another one of these objects named (*) Zulfiqar was used by Ali to win the Battle of Uhud. Only the true heir of Uther Pendragon could pull one of these objects out of a stone. King Arthur wields, for 10 points, what sort of object named Excalibur?", "answer": "Swords", "category": "Mythology"}, {"question": "This philosopher was very attached to his pet poodles, and he criticized Baruch Spinoza\u2019s belief that animals were merely means from which humans were to derive satisfaction. In Friedrich Nietzsche's work Untimely Meditations, this philosopher is described as an educator, (*) whose philosophic genius might revitalize German culture. This philosopher is also credited with defining the phrase \u201cwill to life.\u201d For 10 points, identify this pessimistic German author of The World as Will and Representation.", "answer": "Arthur Schopenhauer", "category": "Philosophy"}, {"question": "A woman with this first name is displeased when her sister-in-law, Lady Susan Vernon, visits her in a short epistolary novel. In another novel by the same author, the protagonist with this first name loves Gothic novels like (*) Castle of Wolfenbach and Mysterious Warnings and is \u201cin training [to become] a heroine.\u201d That character visits Bath with the Allens and marries Henry Tilney. For 10 points, give the given first name of Elizabeth Bennet\u2019s younger sister, Kitty, from Jane Austen\u2019s Pride and Prejudice.", "answer": "Catherine [do NOT accept \u201cKate\u201d]", "subcategory": "Literature British", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "It\u2019s not Tennessee, but this state\u2019s city of Paris constructed a replica Eiffel Tower topped with a hat. This state\u2019s Hill Country is located east of the Big Bend. This state\u2019s panhandle region and that of its northern neighbor border each other and much of the border between that state and this one is formed by the (*) Red River. The Galveston seawall protected major oil facilities around this state\u2019s largest city until Hurricane Ike in 2008. Enron was once headquartered in, for 10 points, what Lone Star State, home to the Dallas-Fort Worth metropolitan area?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "Geography"}, {"question": "In one work by this author, Masha marries Sergey Mikhaylych before their marriage suffers because of her love of society; that work is titled Family Happiness. In the beginning of another of this man\u2019s works, a woman debates with an old man about marriage, and then calls him a Domostroi after he leaves the train. In that work, (*) Pozdnyshev kills his wife after catching her with the violinist, Troukhatchevsky. This author of The Kreutzer Sonata wrote a novella about a magistrate who dies of a wound he receives while hanging curtains, The Death of Ivan Ilyich. For 10 points, name this author of War and Peace.", "answer": "Leo Tolstoy", "subcategory": "Literature European", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "The bassoons imitate the roasting of this animal in the twelfth section of Carmina Burana. An unsuccessful composition called The Building of the Boat was used to create a piece named for this animal, in which this animal is represented by an English horn. This animal is the namesake of a (*) ballet in which the dance of the goblets is performed by Prince Siegfried as he aims a crossbow. For 10 points, Odette is transformed into what title animal in a Tchaikovsky ballet?", "answer": "Swan [prompt on \u201cBird\u201d]", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Audiovisual", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Plan Lazo was developed by the United States to stomp out the \u201cMarquetalia Republics\u201d within this country\u2019s rural heartlands. Those republics had formed in the decade of unrest after the assassination of presidential candidate Jorge Eli\u00e9cer Gaitan in this country, a period known as (*) La Violencia. In this country, the anti-guerrilla operation would have the unexpected effect of galvanizing leftist militias into forming militant groups like FARC. For 10 points, name this South American country formerly home to a vicious cocaine-funded civil war between communist terrorists and right-wing militias.", "answer": "Colombia", "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This experiment was contradicted by an earlier experiment that took place in water and was conducted by Fizeau. Kennedy and Thorndike improved on this experiment to show that its results were independent of velocity. An (*) interferometer was used in this experiment to compare the interference pattern between two beams of light. In this experiment, a beam splitter split light into running in two different directions, and the speed of the two beams was shown to be the same. For 10 points, name this experiment that took place at Case Western Reserve University and disproved the existence of the luminiferous aether.", "answer": "Michelson-Morley Experiment", "subcategory": "Science Physics", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "This ruler\u2019s minister Chanakya outlined his political ideology in the Arthashastra. This ruler, whose empire was chronicled by Megasthenes, signed a treaty with the Seleucid Empire that gave him the territories of Arachosia and Gandhara. This ruler gained power after he defeated the (*) Magadha and Nanda kingdoms. After converting to Jainism, this ruler fasted to death at Shravana Belagola. For 10 points, name this ruler who was the grandfather of Ashoka and the first Mauryan emperor.", "answer": "Chandragupta Maurya [accept Sandrokottus or Androcottus]", "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This artist was reported to have shouted \u201cSpeak! Damn you! Speak!\u201d while carving his favorite work, Habakkuk. His first major statue is situated in a niche of the Orsanmichele as a commission of the linen weaver\u2019s guild. That statue, St. (*) Mark, was quickly eclipsed in popularity by his works in bronze like the equestrian statue of Erasmo da Narni entitled Gattamelata. For 10 points, name this Florentine sculptor who sculpted a famous bronze statue of David.", "answer": "Donatello", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Visual", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "A man of this profession was the title character of Sax Rohmer\u2019s novels and is known for his famous mustache. In another work, Esther Summerson marries an individual with this job. A bespectacled man with this occupation stares over the (*) Valley of Ashes. The alter-ego of a title character with this job beats to death Sir Danvers Carew after taking a serum that allows the protagonist to fulfill his dark dreams. For 10 points, name this profession, the job of characters such as Daneeka, Abraham Van Helsing, and Zhivago.", "answer": "Doctor [accept Physician; anti-prompt on specific types of doctors]", "subcategory": "Literature Other", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "Types of these structures include \u201ccirque\u201d and \u201ctidewater,\u201d the latter of which are a type that terminate into the sea. On Mars, deposits from these structures can be found at many Martian volcanoes. These structures grow at accumulation zones (*) and shrink in ablation zones through a process known as calving. The specific term for the sedimentation left behind by these structures is \u201cmoraine,\u201d and \u201cterminal moraines\u201d mark the maximum advance of these entities. For 10 points, name these dense bodies of moving ice.", "answer": "Glacier", "subcategory": "Science Other", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "A character in this novel hits a police officer named Jerry with his handgun, but is arrested after a fire hose knocks him off of a water tower. In this novel, that man is then questioned about Miss Ashton and Mrs. Clinton\u2019s sister by Buckley. A man in this novel who donates ping pong tables to the South Side Boys Club disapproves of his daughter\u2019s relationship with (*) Jan Erlone. In this novel, that daughter\u2019s bones are later discovered in a furnace in the Dalton's house. For 10 points, name this novel in which the murder of Bessie Mears and Mary Dalton leads to the arrest of Bigger Thomas, written by Richard Wright.", "answer": "Native Son", "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"question": "During this event, a synagogue was forced to hire private security after local police refused to station an officer nearby. During this event, a helicopter crash led to the deaths of two state troopers. This event saw a member of the (*) IWW, Heather Heyer, killed in a terrorist attack by Alex Fields. This event, spearheaded by David Duke and Richard Spencer, led to criticism of the President after a press conference in which he discussed good people being \u201con both sides.\u201d For 10 points, name this event where protesters with tiki torches attempted to stop the removal of Confederate statues in the town housing the main campus of the University of Virginia.", "answer": "Unite the Right Rally [accept clear knowledge equivalent, e.g. Neo-Nazi rally in Charlottesville; prompt on partial answer]", "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"question": "This man compared a crowd to snakes before encouraging them to be charitable. In another tradition, this man anointed Oliver Cowdery to the Aaronic Priesthood, along with Joseph Smith. This man\u2019s father, Zechariah, was made dumb after reacting incredulously to (*) the angel Gabriel\u2019s news of this man\u2019s upcoming birth. His mother, Elizabeth, may have been related to the Virgin Mary, but only the Gospel of Luke claims that. At the request of Salome [sah-low-may], King Herod ordered the beheading of, for 10 points, what man who immersed Jesus in the River Jordan?", "answer": "John the Baptist [prompt on partial answers; do NOT accept \u201cJohn the Evangelist\u201d]", "category": "Religion"}, {"question": "This art movement was heavily influenced by the late works of Paul C\u00e9zanne, such as the Mont Sainte-Victoire series. This art movement was divided into two phases: analytic and synthetic, the latter signifying the introduction of media such as collage. One member of this movement, (*) Juan Gris, painted in the \u201ccrystal\u201d form of this movement, which emphasized an even simpler geometric structure. Georges Braque was the co-founder of, for 10 points, what art movement that fragmented different three-dimensional perspectives onto two-dimensional space and was co-led by Pablo Picasso?", "answer": "Cubism", "subcategory": "Fine Arts Visual", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"question": "Metabolic waste produced from fermentation in this body structure is transported to the liver in the Cori cycle. This tissue is fundamentally composed of I bands, A bands, and a medial H zone. T-tubules traverse the cells of this structure, (*) assisting in the transduction of the of the neurotransmitter acetylcholine. Troponin and tropomyosin facilitate the regulation of the main activity of this organ. This structure is composed of the proteins myosin and actin. For 10 points, name this main organ of contraction, categorized into cardiac, skeletal, and smooth varieties.", "answer": "Muscle [accept specific types]", "subcategory": "Science Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"question": "One of these people served as George W. Bush\u2019s second Attorney General, after John Ashcroft\u2019s resignation, before himself resigning. Another member of this group was Secretary of Housing and Urban Development under Barack Obama and previously keynoted the 2012 D.N.C., while serving as Mayor of (*) San Antonio, Texas. The Zoot Suit riots targeted these people, including those who worked as part of the Bracero Program. The fourth largest ethnic group in the U.S. is, for 10 points, what group whose Chicano movement was led by, among others, Dolores Huerta and Cesar Chavez?", "answer": "Mexican-Americans [accept Chicanos or Chicanas until mentioned; prompt on answers such as \u201cHispanics\u201d or \u201cLatinos\u201d] Tiebreaker", "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"question": "In this character\u2019s first appearance, he is only a week old in the novel The Little White Bird. In a subsequent play, this title character wears clothes made of autumn leaves and cobwebs. He visits Bloomsbury and loses his (*) shadow. This character invites a young girl to be the mother of his gang, children who were lost in Kensington Gardens when they fell out of their prams. In another scene, this character returns to Bloomsbury to bring Jane to Neverland. For 10 points, name this character created by J.M. Barrie, a young boy who refuses to grow up.", "answer": "Peter Pan [accept either] Packet 6 \u2013 Bonuses", "subcategory": "Literature British", "category": "Literature"}], "bonuses": [{"leadin": "The central character of this novella waits eighty-four days before finally catching a fish, only to have it eaten by a shark. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["The Old Man and the Sea", "Santiago", "Joe DiMaggio"], "parts": ["Identify this Ernest Hemingway work about a fisherman.", "This main character of The Old Man and the Sea has an apprentice named Manolin.", "Santiago fantasizes about many things while he is out on the ocean, including dolphins and lions lying on a beach together, and this man, his favorite New York Yankees baseball player."], "subcategory": "Literature American", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "This event took place in the Jornado del Muerto desert near the McDonald Ranch House. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Trinity Test", "Manhattan Project [accept Development of Substitute Materials]", "Hiroshima"], "parts": ["Name this event, which saw the detonation of the first ever atomic bomb at the White Sands Missile Range in New Mexico.", "The Trinity Test was authorized by this project headed by the Department of Energy. Much of their work took place in Oak Ridge, Tennessee.", "The first military deployment of the atomic bomb occurred when the Enola Gay dropped the \u201cLittle Boy\u201d over this city. A memorial dedicated to its victims was visited by Obama in May of 2016."], "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, name these British overseas territories.", "answers_sanitized": ["Saint Helena", "Bermuda", "Pitcairn Islands"], "parts": ["This island in the South Atlantic Ocean was the site of Napoleon\u2019s second exile and death. It forms a British Overseas Territory with Ascension Island and Tristan da Cunha.", "A shipwreck on this island was supposedly the inspiration for Shakespeare\u2019s The Tempest. It also names a \u201ctriangle\u201d known for mysterious disappearances.", "This island chain is the last British holding in the Pacific Ocean. It is mainly inhabited by descendants of mutineers from the HMS Bounty."], "category": "Geography"}, {"leadin": "Answer these questions about the cell membrane, for 10 points each.", "answers_sanitized": ["Phospholipids", "Facilitated diffusion [prompt on \u201cdiffusion\u201d or \u201cpassive transport\u201d]", "Fluid mosaic [prompt on partial answer]"], "parts": ["This class of lipids forms the bilayer of the cell membrane because of their hydrophilic, polar heads and their two hydrophobic, nonpolar tails.", "Aquaporins allow water to cross the cell membrane through this kind of transport that moves molecules and ions through transmembrane or channel proteins.", "This model is used to describe the structure of the cell membrane because it is flexible enough to change shape without breaking and has a variety of molecules embedded into it."], "subcategory": "Science Biology", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, answer these questions about orchestras.", "answers_sanitized": ["Oboe", "Principal", "Concertmaster"], "parts": ["Before an orchestra plays, they must of course tune their instruments. In most full scale orchestras, this double reed instrument provides an A to tune to.", "In each instrument\u2019s section, the first chair player is given this title, which means first. That player is usually responsible for leading and playing solos for that section.", "Specifically, the principal first-violinist is given this title in addition to \u201cfirst chair\u201d and \u201cleader.\u201d This player leads the tuning and signals for the oboe to play an A."], "subcategory": "Fine Arts Auditory", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "Adherents of this religion fast and observe its five main vows during the festival of Paryushan. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Jainism", "Tirthankaras", "Sutras"], "parts": ["Name this religion, whose adherents are separated into the Digambara, or \u201csky-clad\u201d sect, and Svetambara, or \u201cwhite-clad\u201d sect. Members of this religion cannot eat root vegetables.", "Jainism venerates twenty-four of these religious teachers. The last one, Mahavira, recited his teachings to his disciple Gautama Swami, which became the Agamas.", "The first of the Agamas is the \u201cAcharanga\u201d one of these texts, which advocates the proper behavior of a devout Jain. The \u201cLotus\u201d one of these texts in Buddhism emphasizes that anyone can become a Buddha."], "category": "Religion"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, answer these questions about a famous Greek sculpture.", "answers_sanitized": ["Venus de Milo", "Auguste Renoir", "Salvador Dal\u00ed"], "parts": ["This sculpture was created by Alexandros of Antioch, although it was once attributed to the more famous Praxiteles. The goddess depicted in this sculpture is notably missing both of her arms.", "This French painter was displeased with the Venus de Milo and called it a \u201cbig gendarme.\u201d His works include Dance at the Moulin de la Galette and Luncheon of the Boating Party.", "This artist was inspired by the Venus de Milo and sculpted drawers into the figure in his aptly named work Venus de Milo with Drawers. He also featured the sculpture multiple times in his painting The Hallucinogenic Toreador."], "subcategory": "Fine Arts Visual", "category": "Fine Arts"}, {"leadin": "This novel is one of the Four Great Classical Novels of Chinese literature. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Romance of the Three Kingdoms [accept San Guo Yan Yi]", "Reverse psychology [prompt on partial answer]", "Peach"], "parts": ["Name this historical novel written by Luo Guanzhong that describes the turbulent end of the Han dynasty and the namesake period of Chinese history. It features characters like Liu Bei, Guan Yu, and Zhang Fei", "This strategy was most notably used by Zhuge Liang to defend Xicheng, when he calmly played the guqin and ordered all the city gates to be opened. This tactic relies on advocating a certain action with the expectation that the opposite action will occur.", "In Romance of the Three Kingdoms, the three brothers take an oath in a garden named for this fruit. In Journey to the West, Sun Wukong is given the task of protecting a \u201cheavenly garden\u201d named after this fruit. Afterward, Sun Wukong steals this fruit, which is said to grant immortality."], "subcategory": "Literature World", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "A lot of gas laws combine to form the ideal gas law. For 10 points each, name some of them.", "answers_sanitized": ["Boyle\u2019s Law", "Gay-Lussac\u2019s Law", "Ethanol [accept drinking alcohol; prompt on \u201calcohol\u201d]"], "parts": ["This gas law, which states that volume varies inversely with pressure given a constant temperature, was named for the English author of The Skeptical Chymist.", "This law states that the pressure of a fixed volume of gas is directly proportional to the gas\u2019s absolute temperature.", "Gay-Lussac also names a measure for the amount of this substance by volume. This substance is the treatment for methanol poisoning, but in large doses can cause cirrhosis and nausea."], "subcategory": "Science Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This empire gifted an elephant named Abul-Abbas and a water clock to Charlemagne. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Abbasid Caliphate", "Khan [accept Hulagu Khan or Genghis Khan]", "Slaves"], "parts": ["Name this caliphate, whose ruler Harun al-Rashid established the House of Wisdom in its capital of Baghdad. This caliphate defeated the preceding Umayyads at the Battle of the Zab River.", "A man with this surname rolled up the Abbasid caliph into a carpet and trampled over him during the 1258 Siege of Baghdad. Another man with this title destroyed the Khwarezmian Empire after they killed two of his ambassadors.", "The Zanj Rebellion during the Abbasid Caliphate was one of the bloodiest rebellions ever that was led by these people. Mamluks were soldiers who previously had this status."], "subcategory": "History World", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "Before the onset of the Trojan War, Hesiod described the world as being in the Age of Heroes. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Heracles [or Hercules]", "Atalanta", "Calydon [accept Calydonian boar]"], "parts": ["Name this hero who famously slayed the Lernean Hydra as part of his twelve labors, only to have it not count because he was aided by his nephew Iolaus.", "This hero wedded the suitor Hippomenes after being defeated in a foot race. She was the only female Argonaut.", "Atalanta first became prominent after drawing first blood of a nearly invincible boar ravaging this area in Aetolia"], "category": "Mythology"}, {"leadin": "This country fought the Cod Wars with the United Kingdom. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Iceland", "Althing", "Kalmar Union"], "parts": ["Name this deceptively-named island country discovered by the Vikings in search of arable land. Its capital at Reykjavik has been unchanged since the medieval era.", "The Icelandic parliament, the oldest in the world, is known by this name. Public addresses here are given at the law rock.", "As a territory of Norway, Iceland was part of this anti-Hanseatic union that joined Denmark, Sweden, and Norway under a single monarch. This union broke apart when Sweden declared independence under Gustav Vasa."], "subcategory": "History European", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "The narrator of this work implores the reader to call her \u201cMary Beton, Mary Seton, or Mary Carmichael,\u201d claiming her name is not important. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["\u201cA Room of One\u2019s Own\u201d", "Virginia Woolf", "William Shakespeare"], "parts": ["Name this essay, which claims that a woman must have money and the title location in order to write fiction.", "\u201cA Room of One\u2019s Own\u201d was written by this British author, who also wrote about Clarissa Dalloway preparing for a party in Mrs. Dalloway and the Ramsay family in To the Lighthouse.", "In \u201cA Room of One\u2019s Own,\u201d Woolf creates Judith, the fictional sister of this male author, in order to illustrate society\u2019s bias against women. In the essay, Judith dies in obscurity in London, while this author finds success and acclaim."], "subcategory": "Literature British", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "Answer these questions on the achievements of females at the Academy Awards. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Emma Stone", "Whoopi Goldberg [accept Caryn Elaine Johnson]", "Colleen Atwood"], "parts": ["This woman received the Best Actress award for her portrayal of aspiring actress Mia Dolan in La La Land during the 2017 ceremony.", "This African-American comedian, known for playing Celie in The Color Purple, is the only female to have hosted the Oscars four times. She is currently one of the hosts on The View.", "This woman has won the Academy Award for Best Costume Design for Chicago, Memoirs of a Geisha, Alice in Wonderland, and most recently, Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them."], "category": "Trash"}, {"leadin": "These compounds have an associated number that describes the risk of \u201cknocking.\u201d For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Alkanes", "Isomerism [accept Isomers]", "Axial"], "parts": ["Name these saturated hydrocarbons with formula C sub n H sub 2n plus 2. They possess only single bonds, and the simplest of these compounds is methane.", "Alkanes with substitutions possess the cis-trans version of this property. In general, this property refers to molecules having multiple possible chemical structures for one chemical formula. This property has constitutional and stereo varieties.", "The substitutions on an alkane can either be in the equatorial position or in this other position. A ring flip is the interconversion between this position and the equatorial position."], "subcategory": "Science Chemistry", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "Answer the following about <em>Arabian Nights</em>, for 10 points each.", "answers_sanitized": ["Scheherazade", "Sinbad the Sailor", "Open Sesame"], "parts": ["The frame story of Arabian Nights is this woman telling stories to her husband, Shahryar, in order to delay her own execution.", "One well-known story from Arabian Nights is about the seven voyages of this sailor. This man sails to strange lands, including an island which is actually a whale and an island inhabited by giant birds.", "In the story \u201cAli Baba and Forty Thieves,\u201d the title character opens the cave of the thieves with this password. Later, Ali Baba\u2019s brother forgets the password and confuses it with \u201cbarley.\u201d"], "subcategory": "Literature World", "category": "Literature"}, {"leadin": "What good is the right to choose if our choices are predetermined? For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Free Will [prompt on partial answer]", "Drug Addicts [accept equivalents]", "Libertarianism"], "parts": ["Name this philosophical concept, the ability to choose between different courses of action without external influence. Determinists do not believe that human beings have this, as our thoughts are predetermined by physical laws.", "Harry Frankfurt argues that free will can be reconciled with determinism as a psychological state in a thought experiment featuring two of these people.", "There are still those who subscribe to this position that human beings absolutely have free will; it is not to be confused with the freedom-loving political philosophy."], "category": "Philosophy"}, {"leadin": "One algorithm used in this field was nicknamed \u201cindecipherable.\u201d For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["Cryptography [accept Cryptology]", "Factoring [accept Prime Factorization or word forms]", "Alan Turing"], "parts": ["Name this field that deals with the encryption of messages for secret communication.", "The RSA encryption scheme relies on the difficulty of performing this task on a large number. Algorithms that accomplish this task include Pollard\u2019s Rho and can be done in big O of root n time by trial division.", "This cryptanalyst led British efforts to break the German Enigma code during World War II. His namesake machines can read and write symbols on an infinitely long tape."], "subcategory": "Science Computer Science", "category": "Science"}, {"leadin": "This man was the only Admiral of the Navy. For 10 points each:", "answers_sanitized": ["George Dewey", "Spanish-American War", "USS Maine"], "parts": ["Name this general who exclaimed \u201cYou may fire when ready, Gridley\u201d at the Battle of Manila Bay.", "The Battle of Manila Bay was fought in this war that included engagements fought by Teddy Roosevelt's Rough Riders.", "The Spanish-American War was precipitated by the explosion of this ship in Havana Harbor."], "subcategory": "History American", "category": "History"}, {"leadin": "For 10 points each, name these difficult classical pieces.", "answers_sanitized": ["\u201cFlight of the Bumblebee\u201d", "Islamey", "Maurice Ravel"], "parts": ["This interlude from the Rimsky-Korsakov opera The Tale of Tsar Saltan depicts the chaotic movements of the title insect.", "Subtitled \u201cOriental Fantasy,\u201d this notoriously-difficult piano composition by Mily Balakirev was inspired by his trip to the Caucasus.", "This composer\u2019s Gaspard de la Nuit was specifically written to be harder than Islamey. He wrote a more famous piece beginning with a snare drum ostinato; that piece is his Bolero."], "subcategory": "Fine Arts Auditory", "category": "Fine Arts"}]}